# JINGRU LIU

159 University Avenue West, Waterloo, ON, N2L 3E8 | 226-988-4952 | alice33liu@gmail.com | LinkedIn

# **Summary**

A self-motivated individual with a history of success operating under pressure proven in successfully performing a busy retail cashier function. Known for a strong work ethic, excellent communication skills and the ability to deliver a high quality service. Proven leadership skills and finance skills to develop a business plan from scratch in a team. Experienced in numerous programming languages recognized in personal project and as a web developer.

#### **Education**

# **University of Waterloo**

Waterloo, ON

Bachelor of Computing and Financial Management, Honors, Co-op (exp.2020)

Relevant Coursework: Corporate Finance, Management, Accounting, and Programming Skill (DrRacket)

#### **Skills & Abilities**

- Intermediate programming skills in C++, DrRacket,
  Java, HTML/CSS, MySQL, and Excel VBA
- Strong proficiency in Microsoft Office, especially PowerPoint and Excel
- Strong attention to detail and desire to learn in all aspects of work
- Organizational skills necessary for multitasking and keeping consistent and accurate records
- Ability to work effectively individually or as part of a team
- Fluent in English, Mandarin and essential French

# **Experience**

Web Developer, Minerva Web Designs; Waterloo, ON

Sept 2015-Present

- Assisted in planning and design of client web sites, as well as implementing desired features
- Worked collaboratively with design team to plan each feature of client site in order to begin development
- Used HTML5 and CSS to build responsive web pages and unique plugins that fit the purpose of each site

#### Webster Business Plan, Course Work; Waterloo, ON

Nov 2015-Dec 2015

- Developed a sound business plan for new company from conceptual idea in a team of 5
- Conducted thorough market research and analysis using PEST and Porter's Five Forces
- Prepared cash budget and financial statements using Excel

### Cashier, Sbarro; Ottawa, ON

Summer 2015

- Proven ability to answer customers' questions and give information regarding the business procedures and policies in an exact and customer-friendly way
- Working efficiently under pressure
- Received and processed payments by cash, credit and debit card

# Platform Game, Personal Project; Ottawa, ON

Apr 2015-July 2015

- Developed a game similar to Mario and Maple Story with key press controls in Java using Eclipse.
- Implemented collision detection, sound effects, tile sets, maps and player sprite animations.